glocals.com 2019-05-04

# Privacy Policy

**Here are  5 of the most important things, in normal non-lawyer speak. Pls scroll down to read the full binding version.**

1\. We value your privacy. We won't spam you and we won't share your personal details with any 3rd party unless required by law or for the proper functioning of the website as detailed below.

2. When you signup to Glocals, you need to submit some basic information to create your profile. You can modify or delete your information by going to Settings - Edit Profile or Settings \- Delete My Account & Information.

3\. Search Engines index our content. So if you post content to glocals.com, non-members may be able to see this content, together with your user-name and picture. However, non-members will not be able to see your full profile.

4\. We use cookies so we can remember you and understand how you use our site.

5\. We use third party applications and/or service providers for specific site functions like hosting, sending the newsletter & CRM. You can read about the apps we use & the information we share with them below.  

\--------------------------------------------------------------------------------

**glocals.com Privacy Policy**

**Please read this Privacy Policy carefully. By using or accessing the platform (defined below), you acknowledge that you have read, understood, and agree to be bound to all the terms and conditions of this Privacy Policy, and our  Terms of Use (collectively, “User Agreements”).**

**If you do not agree to this Privacy Policy and/or our Terms of Use, please do not access or use the platform.**

**Although we may offer information or services which may be relevant to children, we do not intend for any of our sites or services to be used by children, and we do not intend to collect data from children.

Similarly, we do not intend to collect any sensitive data such as data relating to your health, religion, ethnic background or political views.

**

The Glocals.com platform is owned by GenevaOnline – a Swiss SARL located at Chemin des Fins 25, 1218 Grand Sacconex.

This policy describes the data that we collect from you, why we collect it and what we do with it.

The "data controller" of your personal data (in other words, the organization that determines how your data is used) is GenevaOnline SARL.

​For any questions, feel free to contact us via the 'Feedback' form on this site or by emailing [admin@glocals.com](mailto:admin@glocals.com)

The terms “Glocals”, “Glocals.com”, “GenevaOnline”, “GOL”, “we,” “us,” and “our” include Glocals.com, GenevaOnline SARL and our affiliates. We use the terms “member,” “you,” and “your” to mean any person using or visiting our platform  and/or services, including any organization or person using the Platform on an organization’s behalf. This Privacy Policy applies to the processing of information about members, visitors and other individuals that we collect when you use our Platform, which means any website, application, or services we offer, or when you communicate with us.  
This Privacy Policy does not apply to the information that you may provide to third parties, such as other members, social networks, service providers and others with whom you may share information about yourself.

**What Personal Data Do We Collect and How?**

We collect information about you when you create an account, login to or visit our website and/or communicate with us.

We also collect information, such as usage statistics, by using cookies, server logs, and similar technologies.

**Information You Provide To Us:**  
We collect information you provide directly to us when you create an account, login to or visit our website and/or communicate with us.  
The types of information that we may collect include your name, e-mail, address, gender, date of birth, country of origin, location, occupation, relationship status, basic intro and reason for joining.

We also save any information you post anything on our site (for example: forum posts, activities or events, classifieds posts, photos etc). 

  **Information We Collect Automatically When You Use the Platform:**

When you use our Platform, we may automatically collect information about you, including:

  * Information about your visit to our websites, including information about how and when you came to visit our websites, how you interacted with the websites (pages you viewed or searched for; page response times, download errors, length of visits to certain pages, page interaction information such as scrolling, clicks, and mouse-overs), and where you went next
  * Information about your IP address, your login information if you register on our website, browser type and version, time zone setting, browser plug-in types and versions, operating system and platform, device information
  * Information collected through cookies, web beacons, pixel tags, device identifiers and other technologies
  * Information from third parties providing services to us (including, for example, our hosting provider, our email processor and our analytics provider)
  * If you register or log into your account through a third-party social media service, we will have access to some of your third-party account information from that service, such as your name and other information in that account. We may also have access to third-party account information if you use share or like content from our platform on social media
  * If you communicate with other members, we record data about who you communicated with, when, and in what way 
  * If you create or join a group, we record data about the group you joined 
  * If you create or review a business in our city guide, we record data about the business & the review
  * Our site uses cookies to recognize you when you visit and use the site. This helps us to provide you with a good experience when you browse our site (for example, to remember your preferences) and also allows us to improve our site. Other cookies help us to tailor online advertising based on your interests and behaviour on our website and across the internet. For more information on the cookies we use, the purposes for which we use them and ways to limit the use of cookies and similar technologies in relation to your browsers or devices, please see our Cookie Policy below.

**Invitations and Other Communications to Non-members  **  
glocals.com members can invite friends to join the service by sending invitation emails via our automated invitation system. glocals.com stores the email addresses that members provide so that the respondents may be added to the friend's list of the member sending the invitations, and also to send reminders of the invitations Glocals.com does not sell these email addresses or use them to send any other communication besides invitations, invitation reminders (up to three (3) per email address). Recipients of invitations from glocals.com may contact Glocals.com to request the removal of their information from our database.

**Links**    
glocals.com contains links to other sites. glocals.com is not responsible for the privacy policies and/or practices on other sites. When linking to another site a user should read the privacy policy stated on that site. Our privacy policy only governs information collected on glocals.com.

**Posting content to glocals.com  **  
Please be aware that whenever you post information to glocals.com, the information can be accessed by the public and can in turn be used by those people to send you unsolicited communications, especially if you decide to include your email in your post. Information you post to glocals may be indexed by search engines, which means non-members will be able to see, together with your name and picture, and potentially other information about you.

**​How Do We Use The Data We Collect?**

We use your personal data for a variety of purposes related to the products and services we provide. 

  * To complete certain tasks & processes on our website or within our apps
  * To respond to your questions and comments
  * To measure customer satisfaction and provide customer service (including liaising with merchants to troubleshoot in connection with your purchases or your requests for services)
    * We use your data in this way either because we have a contract with you (for example, your acceptance of our Terms of Service) or because it is in our legitimate interests to do so (for example, it is in our interests to measure customer satisfaction and 'troubleshoot' customer issues)

  * ​F​​or advertising and marketing purposes, including to measure how effective our marketing is: To contact you with daily or weekly emails to let you know about products and services we offer that we think you might be interested in based on your subscribed location and other preferences on your account
  * To measure the effectiveness of our marketing campaigns and our advertising (i.e. so that we can tell what interests our customers and what doesn't)
    * We rely on your consent to contact you directly about the products and services on offer on our site (for example, we will send you Daily Deals emails based on your consent). In other scenarios (for example, measuring the effectiveness of our marketing), we will rely on our legitimate interests as a business, always ensuring that your rights are protected

​

  * For administrative and internal business purposes:  
To ensure that content on our site is presented in the most effective and relevant manner for you and for your device and to tailor the site's experience and content based on the way that you use the site
  * To administer our site and for internal operations, including troubleshooting, data analysis, testing, research, statistical and survey purposes
  * For our internal business purposes, such as analysing and managing our businesses, audits, developing new products or services, enhancing our site, improving our services and products and identifying usage trends. For these purposes, your personal data will be aggregated and looked at on a statistical basis;
    * It is in our legitimate interests as a business to use your data in this way. For example, we have a clear interest in ensuring that our site works properly and that our products and services are high quality and efficient. We will always ensure that your rights are protected.

  * For security and legal and compliance purposes as part of our efforts to keep our site safe and secure
  * To detect or prevent fraud or other illegal activity as we believe to be necessary or appropriate in each case in order to comply with laws or legal process (including laws or legal process in other countries)
  * To protect our rights or property (or the rights or property of others) and to enforce our rights and pursue available remedies;
    * In some cases, we will need to use your personal data to fulfill a legal obligation (for example, if we receive a legitimate request from law enforcement agencies), and in other cases (such as the detection of fraud or ensuring the security of the site) we will rely on our legitimate interests as a business to use your data in this way.

​

**How Do We Share Your Data?**

We will never sell your personal data or give it to anyone else for them to use for their own purposes without making that clear to you. There are, however, various ways in which we will share your data, as set out below:

  * ​ **Sharing with service providers of the products and services we offer:**  
We may host offers on behalf of third party service providers on our website and, as such, we will share some information about you with the merchant when you request it by opting in or filling out a contact form. 

  * **​ Sharing with organisations providing services to us:**  
​We engage various third parties to provide services to us for specific functions, and this will often mean that we need to share your personal data with them (it is in our legitimate interests to do so, since we may not have the capabilities to provide these services ourselves). In each case, we will ensure that these third parties are only allowed to use your personal data in order to provide the relevant services to us. We will always make sure that we use organisations that we trust to look after your personal data appropriately and as required by applicable laws.
  * Some examples of these third parties will include: analytics, website hosting and related infrastructure provision, customer service, auditing, and other similar services.​

  * **Sharing data with online advertising related service providers:**  
We may from time to time work with online advertisers, social media platforms and advertising networks to deliver, tailor and measure advertising to you and others both on the site and elsewhere on the internet (including on social media platforms such as Facebook and Twitter). We also use various tools and products which involve the sharing of data with Google to deliver, measure and tailor our online advertising.
  * The personal data that we allow to be shared with these third parties includes online identifiers such as IP address, data from cookies or similar technologies, or other device related information.
  * Similarly, we may share certain online identifiers with analytics and search engine providers that assist us in the improvement and optimisation of our site.
  * You can choose not to allow your data to be used to deliver targeted advertising by changing your settings within social media platforms.​

  * **Sharing data in connection with changes to our company structure or the ownership of our business:**  
If we sell or propose to sell our business or part of it, we may need to disclose your personal data to prospective buyers.  
Similarly, if there are changes to our company structure or if our ownership changes, we may need to disclose your personal data to the new owners or operators of this site or any of our apps as part of that process.

​

  * **Sharing data to comply with laws:**  
There may be scenarios where we are subject to a legal obligation to disclose or share your personal data, such as with law enforcement agencies or public authorities in order to prevent or detect crime.

​

**International Transfer Of Your Data**  
Some of the processes involved in our use of your personal data may require your data to be stored or processed in countries outside of Europe.

Whenever we send (or permit a third party to send) your personal data outside of Europe, we will make sure that we take steps necessary to protect your data as required by applicable laws. For example, we may implement specific contract terms or we may rely on service providers who adhere to certain compliance programs overseas, or we may select service providers based in countries with strong local laws to protect your personal data.

**Security Of Your Personal Data**

We take the security of your data very seriously and have put physical, technical and administrative strategies, controls and measures in place to help protect your personal data from unauthorised access, use or disclosure as required by law and in accordance with accepted good industry practice.

To help us keep your data safe please choose a strong, secure password, keep your password confidential and avoid sharing it with anyone.

**Retention Of Your Personal Data**

We retain certain information that we collect from you while you are a member of the Platform, and in certain cases where you have deleted your account, for the following reasons:

  * So you can use our Platform
  * To ensure that we do not communicate with you if you have asked us not to
  * To better understand the traffic to our Platform so that we can provide all members with the best possible experience
  * To detect and prevent abuse of our Platform, illegal activities and breaches of our Terms of Service
  * To comply with applicable legal requirements

In broad terms, we will only retain your personal data for as long as is necessary for the purposes described in this privacy policy. This means that the retention periods will vary according to the type of the data and the reason that we have the data in the first place. **Your Rights**

Rights that you may have, depending on the country in which you live, include:

  * Accessing, correcting, updating, or deleting of your information
  * Objecting to processing of your information, asking us to restrict processing of your information, or requesting the portability of your information
  * Opting out from receiving marketing communications that we send you at any time. You can exercise this right by selecting the “unsubscribe” link in the marketing emails we send you. Additionally, you may update your email preferences by changing the settings in your account​
  * Withdrawing your consent at any time if we have collected and processed your information with your consent. Withdrawing your consent will not affect the lawfulness of any processing that we conducted prior to your withdrawal, nor will it affect processing of your information conducted in reliance on lawful processing grounds other than consent
  * Complaining to a data protection authority about our collection and use of your information. For more information, please contact your local data protection authority

​

**Changes To Our Privacy Policy**

Any changes we may make to our privacy policy in the future will be posted on this site. We may also email you if the changes require so and if we have your email address. Please check back frequently to see any updates or changes to our privacy policy.

**Cookie Policy**

We and our service providers use cookies and other technologies to provide our Platform and to enhance your experience. This Cookie Policy sets out some further detail on how and why we use these technologies on our Platform, which includes any website, application, or service we offer. By using our Platform, you consent to storage and access to cookies and other technologies on your device, in accordance with this Cookie Policy.

**What are Cookies?**

Cookies are small data files which are downloaded to your device when you visit a website. Cookies are then sent back to the originating website on each subsequent visit, or to another website that recognizes that cookie. Cookies are useful because they allow us to recognize your device.

**How We Use Cookies**

We use cookies for the following purposes:

  * Authentication: We use cookies to recognize you if you are logged in to our Platform. This lets us personalize your experience on or with the Platform in the ways described below
  * Security: We use cookies to support or enable security features we have deployed, and to help us detect malicious activity and violations of our Terms of Service. These cookies help us prevent fraudulent use of login credentials
  * Services, features, and preferences: We use cookies to provide functionality and help us deliver our products and services according to your preferences
  * Performance, Analytics and Research: We use cookies to help us analyze how the Platform is being accessed and used, and enable us to track performance of the Platform. This helps us to understand, improve, and research features and content on the Platform. We may also use other services, such as Google Analytics or other third-party cookies, to assist with analyzing performance on our Platform. As part of providing these services, these service providers may use cookies and the technologies described below to collect and store information about your device, such as time of visit, pages visited, time spent on each page of the Platform, links clicked and conversion information, IP address, browser, mobile network information, and type of operating system used
  * Ads: We may partner with third party publishers, advertising networks and service providers to manage ads on our sites. Our third party partners may set cookies on your device or use the technologies described below to gather information about your activities on the Platform and other sites and online services you use, in order to provide you with ads that match member profiles or interests
  * Third party advertisers: We may work with advertisers to serve ads that may be relevant to you based on your inferred interests, location or other information collected about you, which may use a cookie or the technologies described below, on our Platform, or on a third party website or online service. The placing of these technologies on your device may enable you to be identified across multiple websites and online services.

​

**Duration of Cookies**  
Some cookies, known as "session cookies", will stay on your device only for as long as you are accessing our Platform. Others, known as "persistent cookies", are stored on your device for longer periods.

**Other Technologies**

  * Pixels tags. Pixel tags (which are also called clear GIFs, web beacons, or pixels), are small pieces of code that can be embedded on websites and emails. Pixels tags may be used to learn how you interact with our site pages and emails, and this information helps us and our partners provide you with a more tailored experience.
  * Device Identifiers. A device identifier is a unique label can be used to identify a mobile device. Device identifiers may be used to track, analyze and improve the performance of the Platform and ads delivered.
  * Local storage. Local storage is an industry-standard technology that enables the storage and retrieval of data on a computer, mobile phone or other device. Local storage may be used to store member preferences on devices.

​

**Opting Out Of Cookies**

Most devices and web browsers are set to accept cookies by default. If you prefer, you may be able to remove or reject cookies. You can learn more about how to block cookies by visiting allaboutcookies.org. Please note that if you choose to remove or reject cookies, this could affect the availability and functionality of our Platform.  
You may also be able to control advertising cookies provided by publishers, for example Google's Ad Preference Manager. Your device may also include a feature that allows you to opt out of having certain information collected through apps used for behavioral advertising purposes. Note that even if you choose to opt out of receiving targeted advertising, you may still receive advertising, although it should not be tailored to your interests or activities.  

Overall, cookies help us provide you with a better website experience, by enabling us to monitor which pages you find useful and which you do not. A cookie in no way gives us access to your computer or any information about you, other than the data you choose to share with us.
